Labyrinth 1986 魔幻迷宮
享森同仁公司和盧卡斯 電影有限公司聯合出品
導演：吉姆·享森
領銜主演：戴維·鮑伊
珍妮弗·康奈利
片名：魔幻迷宮
DAVID BOWIE - UNDERGROUND
把孩子給我
Give me the child.
經歷數之不盡的 艱難限阻…
Through dangers untold and hardships unnumbered...
我終於到了城堡 在格布林鬼城那裡…
I have fought my way to the castle beyond the Goblin City...
找回了被你偷走的小孩
to take back the child that you have stolen.
因為我的毅力 同你一樣堅韌…
For my will is as strong as yours...
而且我的國度一樣的偉大…
and my kingdom is as great...
因為我的毅力同你一樣堅韌 我的國度一樣的偉大…
For my will is as strong as yours, my kingdom as great...
該死
Damn.
噢 我怎麼也記不住這一行
Oh, I can never remember that line.
你的法力並不強過我
"You have no power over me."
噢 墨林
Oh, Merlin.
噢不 墨林 難以置信已經7點了！
Oh, no, Merlin. I don't believe it. It's 7:00!
快點快點
Come on. Come on!
噢那可不是個神話
Oh, it's not fair!
噢真的
Oh, really.
- 對不起  - 別站在雨裡快進來
- I'm sorry. - Don't stand in the rain. Come on.
好快進去墨林
All right. Come on, Merlin.
- 快點  - 狗不行
- Come on. - Not the dog.
- 但下著這麼大雨  - 別廢話讓它去車庫
- But it's pouring. - Go on, into the garage.
去吧墨林去車庫去
Go on, Merlin. Go into the garage.
去
Go.
- 莎拉你遲了一個小時了  - 我說了對不起了
- Sarah, you're an hour late. - I said I was sorry!
請讓我說完
Please let me finish.
- 你爸爸和我很少出去  - 你每一個週末都出去玩
- Your father and I go out rarely. - You go out every single weekend.
我只是讓你代看一下你弟弟 這對你做的事又沒有什麼影響
I ask you to baby-sit only if it won't interfere with your plans.
你根本不知道我打算做什麼 你根本不曾問過我
You don't know what my plans are. You don't even ask me anymore.
我猜你會跟我說你有個約會 如果你有約會我會很高興
I assume you'd tell me you had a date. I'd like it if you had a date.
- 在你這年紀你應該約會  - 莎拉你回來拉
- You should have dates at your age. - Sarah, you're home.
- 我們正擔心你呢  - 我就不能做什麼好事是嗎？
- We were worried about you. - I can't do anything right, can I?
她待我就像個 神話裡的可惡的後母
She treats me like a wicked stepmother in a fairy story no matter what I say.
我會跟她談談
I'll talk to her.
經歷了未知的危險…
Through dangers untold...
和數不盡的艱辛…
and hardships unnumbered...
我終於到了這裡 這個城堡…
I have fought my way here to the castle...
在格布林鬼城那裡…
beyond the Goblin City...
找回了小孩…
to take back the child...
你偷走的那個小孩
that you have stolen.
- 我能跟你談談嗎？  - 沒什麼好談的
- Can I talk to you? - There's nothing to talk about!
快點你們要遲到了
Hurry. You're gonna be late.
聽著我們餵過了托比 已經把他放到床上了
Listen, we fed Toby and put him to bed.
我們現在得離開了 我們會在半夜裡回來
We do have to leave now, but we'll be back around midnight.
你真的想同我談談是嗎？
You really wanted to talk to me, didn't you?
還是把門關上吧
Practically broke down the door.
蘭斯洛特
Lancelot!
有人又到過我的屋 碰過我的東西
Someone has been in my room again.
討厭討厭！
I hate that. I hate it!
我恨你我恨你
I hate you. I hate you!
幫幫我  把我從這個該死的地方帶走
Someone save me, take me away from this awful place!
想要什麼？ 你想聽故事嗎？
What do you want? You want a story, huh?
好吧
Okay.
從前有一個 漂亮的小女孩…
Once upon a time there was a beautiful, young girl...
她的繼母總是讓她留在家裡看孩子
whose stepmother always made her stay home with the baby.
這個小孩被寵壞了 什麼都想要…
The baby was a spoiled child and wanted everything for himself...
而這個小女孩簡直就是個奴隸
and the young girl was practically a slave.
但是沒人知道…
But what no one knew...
格布林鬼城的國王愛上了這個女孩…
was that the king of the goblins had fallen in love with the girl...
並且給了她一些魔力
and he had given her certain powers.
這樣一天晚上…
So one night...
當這個小孩虐待她的時候…
when the baby had been particularly cruel to her...
她召喚了妖精來幫她
she called on the goblins for help.
聽著
Listen.
「快說那些話」妖精們說
"Say your right words," the goblins said.
「我們會把孩子帶到格布林鬼城…
"And we'll take the baby to the Goblin City...
你就自由了」
and you will be free. "
但是女孩知道 格布林鬼城的國王…
But the girl knew that the king of the goblins...
會永遠永遠把孩子留在城堡裡…
would keep the baby in his castle forever and ever and ever...
並且把他變成個妖精
and turn it into a goblin.
因此女孩被默默地折磨著…
So the girl suffered in silence...
直到一天晚上 當她經受一整天的家務活的勞累…
until one night, when she was tired from a day of housework...
之後又被後母的尖刻的言語所傷…
and she was hurt by the harsh words of her stepmother...
她再也不能忍受了
and she could no longer stand it...
噢 好吧
Oh, all right!
別鬧了 來吧
Knock it off. Come on.
住口
Stop it!
我會這樣說
I'll say the words.
不 我不會 我不會這麼說
No, I mustn't. I mustn't say.
我希望…
I wish...
I wish.
- 她就要說了  - 說什麼？
- She's going to say it. - Say what?
- 閉嘴  - 對不起
- Shut up. - Sorry.
你們閉嘴
You shut up.
聽著她就要說了
Listen. She's going to say the words.
我都等不及了
I can bear it no longer!
格布林鬼城的國王 格布林鬼城的國王 無論你在哪裡…
Goblin King, Goblin King, wherever you may be...
把我的這個孩子帶走吧 離我遠遠的
take this child of mine far away from me!
- 不  - 不是這個
- No! - That's not it.
她從哪裡學來的這些垃圾？ 根本不是以「我希望」開頭的
Where'd she learn that rubbish? It doesn't even start with "I wish."
托比別哭了
Toby, stop it!
我希望我知道該說什麼 才能讓妖精把你捉去
I wish I did know what to say to make the goblins take you away.
我希望妖精們會來 現在就把你捉走
"I wish the goblins would come and take you away right now."
這不難是嗎？
That's not hard, is it?
我希望
I wish...
- 她說了嗎？  - 閉嘴
- Did she say it? - Shut up!
我希望妖精們來把你帶走
I wish the goblins would come and take you away.
就現在
Right now.
托比？
Toby?
托比你還好嗎？
Toby, are you all right?
為什麼你不哭了？
Why aren't you crying?
你是他是嗎？你是格布林鬼城的國王
You're him, aren't you? You're the goblin king.
請把我的弟弟還給我 如果真是那樣
I want my brother back, please, if it's all the same.
說過的話就是說了
What's said is said.
可是我不是那個意思
But I didn't mean it.
- 噢 你不是那個意思  - 求求你
- Oh, you didn't. - Please.
他在哪裡？
Where is he?
你很清楚他在哪裡
You know very well where he is.
請把他還給我
Please bring him back. Please.
莎拉…
Sarah...
回到你的房間裡去…
go back to your room...
玩你的玩具 擺弄你的衣服
play with your toys and your costumes.
忘了孩子
Forget about the baby.
我不能
I can't.
我給你帶了個禮物
I've brought you a gift.
- 是什麼？  - 是個水晶球
- What is it? - It's a crystal.
沒什麼特別
Nothing more.
但如果你這樣…
But if you turn it this way...
看裡面
Iook into it.
它會顯現出你的夢
It will show you your dreams.
這可不是給普通女孩的禮物…
But this is not a gift for an ordinary girl...
誰會在意一個哭鬧的小孩
who takes care of a screaming baby.
想要它嗎？
Do you want it?
那就忘了孩子吧
Then forget the baby.
我不能
I can't.
我感謝您為我做的這些 但是我想要回我的弟弟
I appreciate what you're trying to do for me, but I want my brother back.
- 他一定很害怕  - 莎拉
- He must be so scared. - Sarah.
別拒絕我
Don't defy me.
你可不能跟我鬥
You're no match for me.
但我得要回我的弟弟
But I have to have my brother back.
他在那裡在我的城堡裡
He's there, in my castle.
你還想去找他嗎？
Do you still want to look for him?
就是在格布林 鬼城那個城堡嗎？
Is that the castle beyond the Goblin City?
回去吧莎拉 回去否則就太遲了
Turn back, Sarah. Turn back before it's too late.
我不能
I can't.
你還不明白我說的嗎？
Don't you understand that I can't?
真可惜
What a pity.
它看起來並不那麼遠
It doesn't look that far.
比你想像的遠時間很短
It's further than you think. Time is short.
你有13個小時來穿過迷宮…
You have 13 hours in which to solve the labyrinth...
要趕在你的小弟弟…
before your baby brother...
成為我們中的一員之前…
becomes one of us...
永遠地
forever.
真可惜
Such a pity.
迷宮
The labyrinth.
看起來並不那麼難
It doesn't look that hard.
好吧走吧
Well, come on, feet.
- 打擾了？  - 噢 打擾了
- Excuse me? - Oh, excuse me!
噢 是你
Oh, it's you.
打擾了 我必須得穿過這個迷宮 你能幫我嗎？
Excuse me, but I have to get through this labyrinth. Can you help me?
噢 多可愛啊
Oh, how sweet.
五十七
Fifty-seven!
- 你怎麼能？  - 是的
- How could you? - Yeah.
可憐的小東西
Poor thing.
你這個怪物 噢
You monster. Ow!
她咬我
It bit me!
那你希望小精靈做什麼？
What did you expect fairies to do?
我以為她們會滿足人們的願望
I thought they did nice things like granting wishes.
啊？看來你什麼都不知道 是吧？
Huh? Shows what you know, don't it?
- 五十八  - 你真可惡
- Fifty-eight. - You're horrible.
啊？不 不是這樣
Huh? No, I ain't.
我是霍格 你是誰？
I'm Hoggle. Who are you?
我也想問你呢
That's what I thought.
五十九
Fifty-nine.
你知道迷宮的門在哪裡嗎？
Do you know where the door to the labyrinth is?
- 也許  - 在哪裡？
- Maybe. - Where is it?
噢 小東西
Oh, you little...
六十
Sixty!
- 我說它在哪裡？  - 什麼在哪裡？
- I said, where is it? - Where is what?
- 門  - 什麼門？
- The door. - What door?
看來不可能從你那裡問出點什麼來
It's hopeless asking you anything.
那是因為你沒有問對問題
Not if you ask the right questions.
怎樣我才能 進入那個迷宮啊？
How do I get into the labyrinth?
這還差不多
Now that's more like it.
你從這裡進去
You gets in there.
你真的要進去是嗎？
You really going in there, are you?
是的
Yes.
恐怕我必須得去
I'm afraid I have to.
挺容易是嗎？
Cozy, isn't it?
現在你是向左還是向右？
Now, would you go left or right?
- 兩面看起來都一樣  - 嗯你不會走得太遠的
- They both look the same. - Well, you're not gonna get very far.
- 你會去哪邊？  - 我？
- Which way would you go? - Me?
兩面我都不去
I wouldn't go either way.
如果你只願意幫忙到這裡的話 你可以走了
If that's all the help you're gonna be, you can just leave.
你知道你的問題在哪嗎？ 你得自己努力
You know your problem? You take too many things for granted.
拿這個迷宮來說
Take this labyrinth...
即使你到了它的中間 你也走不出來
Even if you get to the center, you'll never get out again.
- 那是你的看法  - 至少比你的好
- That's your opinion. - It's a lot better than yours.
就算這樣也多謝你 霍格特
Thanks for nothing, Hogwart.
是霍格 別說我沒警告你
It's Hoggle! And don't say I didn't warn you.
什麼「迷宮」啊？ 沒有拐彎也沒有拐角
What do they mean, "labyrinth"? There aren't any turns or corners.
只是不斷延伸下去
It just goes on and on.
或許它有盡頭
Maybe it doesn't.
或許只是我以為它有沒有
Maybe I'm just taking it for granted that it does.
您好
'Allo.
是你說「哈嘍」的嗎？
Did you say "hello"?
不 我是說「啊嘍」 不過也差不多了
No, I said "'allo," but that's close enough.
- 你是只蠕蟲是嗎？  - 沒錯
- You're a worm, aren't you? - That's right.
或許你知道怎樣通過這個迷宮吧？
You don't by any chance know the way through this labyrinth?
誰 我？我我只是條蟲子
Who, me? No, I'm just a worm.
進來見見我太太吧
Come inside, meet the missus.
不謝謝你 我先得搞定這個迷宮
No, thank you, but I have to solve this labyrinth.
可是這條巷即沒有拐彎又沒有出口 什麼都沒有
But there aren't any turns or any openings or anything.
一望又沒有盡頭
It just goes on and on.
你只是看不到 這裡到處都是出口 但你卻看不見
You ain't looking right. It's full of openings, but you ain't seeing 'em.
- 出口在哪？  - 穿過那兒就有一個
- Where are they? - There's one just across there.
就在你前面
It's right in front of ya.
沒有啊
No, there isn't.
進來喝杯茶吧
Come inside and have a nice cup of tea.
- 但這裡沒有出口啊  - 肯定有
- But there isn't an opening. - Of course there is.
你試著走過去 你就明白我的意思了
You try walking through it. You'll see what I mean.
什麼？
What?
繼續
Go on then.
那只是一堵牆 沒有進去的路啊
That's just wall. There's no way through.
這裡的東西並不總跟你所看到的一樣
Things are not always what they seem in this place.
所以你不能光看表面
So you can't take anything for granted.
嘿
Hey!
- 繼續  - 謝謝你
- Hang on. - Thank you.
- 您真幫了我的大忙  - 別去那邊
- That was incredibly helpful. - Don't go that way.
- 什麼？  - 我說別去那邊
- What was that? - I said, don't go that way.
絕對不要走這條路
Never go that way.
噢多謝
Oh. Thanks.
如果她堅持走那條路的話…
If she had kept on going down that way...
那她很快就會到城堡了
she'd had gone straight to that castle.
托比
Toby.
我來啦 托比
I'm coming, Toby.
把這個還給我 快點 離我遠點
Give me back this! Go on, get off me.
別走這條路 你在說什麼？
Stay out of the way. What are you talking about?
走走走
Walk, walk, walk.
- 你讓我想起了小孩  - 什麼小孩？
- You remind me of the babe. - What babe?
- 擁有魔法的小孩  - 什麼魔法？
- The babe with the power. - What power?
-  伏都魔法  - 誰會魔法？
- The power of voodoo. - Who do?
- 你會  - 會什麼？
- You do. - Do what?
讓我想起了小孩
Remind me of the babe.
安靜點 一個小妖精
Quiet! A goblin babe.
嗯？
Well?
DAVID BOWIE - DANCE MAGIC
嘿 出了什麼事嗎？
Hey, what goes on?
你媽媽是個土豚
Your mother is an aardvark!
9個小時零23分鐘後…
In 9 hours and 23 minutes...
你就是我的了
you'll be mine.
- 你明白了嗎？  - 我明白了
- You got it? - I got it.
- 不錯  - 噓
- Good. - Shh!
有人改了我的標記
Someone has been changing my marks.
這真是個可怕的地方 這不公平
What a horrible place this is. It's not fair!
你說的對 這不公平
That's right. It's not fair.
而這只是其中一部分
But that's only half of it.
- 一分鐘之前這裡還是個死胡同  - 不 在你後面的才是死胡同
- This was a dead end a minute ago. - No, that's the dead end behind you.
它總是在變 我該怎麼辦呢？
It keeps changing. What am I supposed to do?
唯一的出路 就在這其中的一個門
The only way out of here is to try one of these doors.
其中一個通向迷宮中間的城堡
One of them leads to the castle at the center of the labyrinth.
- 另一個通向…  - 哺哺哺哺
- And the other one leads to... - Boom-boom-ba-boom.
死亡
Certain death.
哪個是哪個？
Which one is which?
- 我們不能告訴你  - 為什麼不能？
- We can't tell you. - Why not?
- 我們不知道  - 但就是這樣
- We don't know. - But they do.
哦 那我就去問他們
Oh. Then I'll ask them.
不 你不能問我們倆 你只能問我們其中一個
No, you can't ask us. You can only ask one of us.
這是規則 而且我得警告你…
It's in the rules, and I should warn you...
我們其中一人總是說實話…
one of us always tells the truth...
而另一人總是說慌
and one of us always lies.
這也是規則 他總是說謊
That's a rule too. He always lies.
- 我沒有 我講的是實話  - 哦 你看這謊說的
- I do not. I tell the truth. - Oh, what a lie.
他說謊
He's the liar.
好吧 回答是或不是
All right. Answer yes or no.
他會告訴我這扇門是通向城堡的嗎？
Would he tell me that this door leads to the castle?
- 你認為呢？  - 我不知道
-What do you think? -l don't know.
是的
Yes.
那麼另一扇門通向城堡…
Then the other door leads to the castle...
而這扇門通向死亡
and this door leads to certain death.
- 噢！  - 你怎麼知道？
- Ooh! - How do you know?
- 他可能在說實話  - 那麼你卻不會
- He could be telling the truth. - But then you wouldn't be.
因此如果你告訴我他說是 我就知道答案是不
So if you told me that he said yes, I know the answer is no.
- 但我也可能在說實話  - 那麼他說謊也行啊
- But I could be telling the truth. - But then he would be lying.
如果你告訴我他說是 我知道答案仍然是否
So if you told me that he said yes, I know the answer would still be no.
等一等 是這樣嗎？
Wait a minute. Is that right?
我不知道 我搞不清楚
I don't know. I've never understood it.
就是這樣 我想出來了
No, it's right. I figured it out.
以前我就想不出來
I could never do it before.
我想我越來越聰明了 這是小菜一碟
I think I'm getting smarter. This is a piece of cake.
救命啊！
Help!
不要這樣！救命啊！
Stop it! Help!
你不是喊救命嗎？ 我們正在救你
What do you mean, "help"? We are helping.
我們是救命手
We're helping hands.
你們弄痛我了
You're hurting.
你要我們放手嗎？
Would you like us to let go?
不
No!
那好 哪一邊？
Well, then come on, which way?
哪一邊？
Which way?
上還是下？
Up or down?
- 噢  - 說啊 說啊
- Oh. - Come on, come on.
我們沒時間磨蹭
We haven't got all day.
看來這個決定很重大
Well, it's a big decision for her.
你想去哪一邊啊？
Which way do you want to go, hmm?
是啊 哪一邊？
Yes, which way?
既然我在向下 那就下吧
Well, since I'm pointed that way, I guess I'll go down.
她選擇下
She chose down.
她選擇下？
She chose down?
- 錯了嗎？  - 太遲了
- Was that wrong? - Too late now.
她掉進了地牢
She's in the oubliette.
住口！她不應該來到地牢
Shut up! She should not have gotten as far as the oubliette.
- 她現在應該放棄了  - 她不會放棄的
- She should have given up by now. - She'll never give up.
不會嗎？ 矮子會帶她回到入口處
Won't she? The dwarf's about to lead her back to the beginning.
當她意識到要從頭開始 就會馬上放棄
She'll soon give up when she realizes she has to start all over again.
那麼笑吧
Well, laugh.
是誰？
Who's there?
是我
Me.
- 噢是你  - 嗯是的…
- Oh, it's you. - Oh, yes, well...
我一見到你 就知道你將會有麻煩…
I knew you were gonna get into trouble as soon as I met you...
所以我來幫你了
so I've come to give you a hand.
你在到處看呢 不是嗎？
Oh, you're looking around now, aren't you?
我想你應該發現這裡沒有門
I suppose you noticed there ain't no doors.
只有那個洞口
Only the hole.
這是一間地牢 迷宮裡到處都是
This is an oubliette. The labyrinth's full of them.
- 真的？你怎麼知道的？  - 噢 真笨
- Really? How do you know that? - Oh, don't sound so smart.
- 你不知道地牢是什麼  - 你知道嗎？
- You don't know what an oubliette is. - Do you?
當然那是你把別人關起來…
Yes, it's a place you put people...
讓他們忘記自己的地方
to forget about 'em.
現在你要做的 就是離開這裡
Now, what you've gotta do is get out of here.
碰巧我知道一條捷徑…
And it so happens that I know a short cut...
能夠離開迷宮
out of the whole labyrinth from here.
不 我現在不打算放棄
No, I'm not giving up now.
我都走這麼遠了
I've come too far.
- 我很好  - 你當然很好
- No, I'm doing okay. - Of course you are.
但是被困在這裡就不好了
But it gets a lot worse from here on in.
你為什麼這麼關心我？
Why are you so concerned about me?
哦 我就是這樣的
Well, I am, that's all.
不想看到這麼年輕漂亮的女孩 被困在又黑又恐怖的地牢裡
Nice, young girl. Terrible, black oubliette.
你喜歡珠寶 對嗎？
You like jewelry, don't you?
幹嘛？
Why?
如果你幫我走出迷宮 我給你這個
If you help me solve the labyrinth, I'll give you this.
你很喜歡 是嗎？
You like it, don't you?
- 一般般  - 那好
- So-so. - Oh. Okay.
這樣吧 你把手鐲給我…
Tell you what... you give me the bracelet...
我就帶你離開迷宮
and I'll show you the way out of the labyrinth.
- 你一定要這麼做  - 是的
- You were gonna do that anyway. - Yes.
這樣做是對你示好的姿態
That's what would make it a particularly nice gesture on your part.
這樣吧…
I'll tell you what...
如果你不帶我去迷宮中心 盡量把我帶近一些
if you won't take me to the center, take me as far as you can.
- 然後我自己走  - 這是什麼做的？
- Then I'll do it on my own. - What is that anyway?
塑料
Plastic.
那麼我答應你…
I don't promise nothing, but...
我盡量把你帶近些 然後你自己走 是嗎？
I'll take you as far as I can, then you're on your own, right?
- 是  - 那好
- Right. - Right.
喔 塑料的！
Wow. Plastic!
走吧
Here we go.
該死的
Damn.
垃圾房
Broom closet.
不是每一次都靈
Well, can't be right all the time.
對了 來吧
This is it. Come on then.
- 這邊  - 不要往前走了- This way. - Don't go on.
趁你還有機會 趕快回去吧
Go back while you still can.
這條路不對
This is not the way.
當心 不要再向前了
Take heed and go no further.
小心 小心
Beware. Beware.
就快來不及了
Soon it will be too late.
唉！別理它們
Yeah! Don't pay any attention to them.
它們是假警報 在迷宮到處都可以看到
They're just false alarms. You get a lot of them in the labyrinth.
特別是當你走對路時
Especially when you're on the right track.
- 不 你走錯路了  - 住口
- Oh, no, you're not. - Oh, shut up.
- 對不起 我只是在工作  - 沒必要對我們說
- Sorry. Just doing my job. - You don't have to do it to us.
- 當心了  - 得了
- Beware for... - Just forget it.
讓我說吧 我很久沒說話了
Oh, please, I haven't said it for such a long time.
也好 不過別指望我們會有多大的反應
Oh, all right, but don't expect a big reaction.
不不不 當然不會
No, no, no, of course not.
你們正在走向毀滅
For the path you will take will lead to certain destruction.
- 太謝謝你了  - 噢
- Thank you very much. - Uh-oh.
噢 不好
Oh, no.
我們碰到什麼了？
What have we here?
- 沒什麼  - 沒什麼？
- Nothing. - Nothing?
沒什麼？沒什麼？
Nothing? Nothing?
沒什麼 哇啦啦
Nothing, tra-la-la.
國王陛下 見到你太意外了
Your Majesty, what a nice surprise.
- 你好 霍特沃得  - 霍格特
- Hello, Hedgewart. - Hogwart.
霍格！
Hoggle!
霍格 你在幫助這個女孩嗎？
Hoggle, can it be that you're helping this girl?
幫助？這是什麼話？
Helping? In what sense?
我是說你正在帶她到城堡
In the sense that you're leading her towards the castle.
不我在帶她到入口處 國王陛下
No, I was taking her back to the beginning, Your Majesty.
什麼？
What?
我告訴她 我會幫她走進迷宮
I told her I was going to help her solve the labyrinth.
我在騙她 實際上…
A little trickery on my part. But actually...
你手腕上的塑料是什麼？
What is that plastic thing 'round your wrist?
噢 這個！
Oh, this!
天哪 這是哪來的？
My goodness, where did this come from?
- 希格…  - 霍格
- Higgle... - Hoggle.
如果我知道你在背叛我…
If I thought for one second that you were betraying me...
我就不得不把你倒掛在永久惡臭的沼澤上
I'd be forced to suspend you headfirst in the Bog of Eternal Stench.
不要 國王陛下！ 不要那裡！
No, Your Majesty! Not the Eternal Stench!
怕了嗎 霍格！
Oh, yes, Hoggle!
你呢 莎拉
And you, Sarah.
覺得我的迷宮怎樣？
How are you enjoying my labyrinth?
小菜一碟
It's a piece of cake.
噢！
Oh!
真的？那麼 把時間撥快點把？
Really? Then how about upping the stakes?
哼？
Hmm?
這不公平！
That's not fair!
你說很多次了
You say that so often.
我想知道你和什麼比較
I wonder what your basis for comparison is.
迷宮是小菜一碟 是嗎？
So the labyrinth's a piece of cake, is it?
那麼看看你怎麼對付這個小玩意
Well, let's see how you deal with this little slice.
噢不 是掃除機！
Oh, no, the cleaners!
- 什麼？  - 快跑！
- What? - Run!
你還好吧？
You okay?
來吧！
Come on!
快點！
Faster!
掃除機！惡臭沼澤！
The cleaners! The Bog of Stench!
你讓他認真起來了
You sure got his attention.
啊 這正是我們要的
Ah, this is what we need.
一個梯子 來吧
A ladder. Follow me.
你剛才想把我帶回入口處 我現在如何相信你？
How can I trust you now that I know you were taking me back to the beginning?
我沒有
I wasn't.
我告訴他我在帶你回入口處 是為了分散他的注意
I told him I was taking you back to the beginning to throw him off the scent.
霍格，我如何相信你的話呢？
Hoggle, how can I believe anything you say?
好吧 這麼說吧
Well, let me put it this way.
你還有什麼選擇呢？
What choice have you got?
那倒是
You're right.
看來你開始瞭解我的處境了
You see, you've gotta understand my position.
我是膽小鬼 佳拉斯嚇倒我了
I'm a coward, and Jareth scares me.
- 什麼樣的處境？  - 沒地位 我認為
- What kind of position is that? - No position. That's my point.
如果你聞過永久惡臭的沼澤…
You wouldn't be so brave if you'd ever smelled...
你就不會這麼勇敢了
the Bog of Eternal Stench.
那是…那是…
It's... It's...
真的很臭嗎？
Is that all it does, is smell?
相信我 是真的
Believe me, that's enough.
更糟糕的是 萬一你不幸…
But the worst thing is, if you so much...
把腳踏進惡臭沼澤…
as put a foot in the Bog of Stench...
你的餘生都會很臭
you'll smell bad for the rest of your life.
洗不掉的
It'll never wash off.
我們到了 從現在起你要靠自己了
Here we are then. You're on your own from now on.
- 什麼？  - 到此為止 我走了
- What? - That's it. I quit.
等一等
Wait a minute.
我遵守諾言了 我說過我能帶多遠就多遠
I didn't promise nothin'. I said I'd take you as far as I could go.
你這個小騙子 你無恥
You little cheat. You nasty little cheat.
別為難我了 我沒有自尊
Don't try to embarrass me. I've got no pride.
真的？
Oh, yeah?
這是我的珠寶！
But them's my jewels!
還給我 還給我 把它們還給我
You give 'em back. Give them back. Give those back.
把它們還給我！
Give those back to me!
現在城堡就在那邊 我們該走哪邊呢？
Now, there's the castle. Which way should we try?
那是我的財產 這不公平！
Them's my rightful property. It's not fair!
就是不公平的
No, it isn't.
事實就是這樣
But that's the way it is.
不好意思 你能幫幫我嗎？
Excuse me, please, but can you help me?
噢 小女孩！
Oh, a young girl!
他是誰？
And who is this?
- 我朋友  - 是啊
- My friend. - Oh, yes.
有什麼能幫你？
And what can I do for you?
麻煩你告訴我… 就是…
Please, can you tell... That is...
我要去迷宮中央的城堡
I have to get to the castle at the center of the labyrinth.
你知道該怎麼走嗎？
Do you know the way?
那麼
Well, yes, now.
你想要去城堡
You want to get to the castle.
腦筋不是很好啊？
How's that for brain power, huh?
安靜！
Be quiet!
啊 生氣了
Ah, nuts.
那麼 小姐…
So, young woman...
向前的路有時是往回的
the way forward is sometimes the way back.
你會聽這個廢物的話嗎！
Will you listen to this crap!
- 你靜一點好嗎！  - 好 對不起
- Will you please be quiet! - Sorry. All right.
- 好嗎  - 好！
- Okay. - Okay!
- All right. - All right!
- 什麼？  - 對不起
- What? - Sorry.
說完了嗎？
Finished?
是
Yes.
小姐 很多時候…
Quite often, young lady...
看起來我們哪裡也去不了 但是事實上…
it seems like we're not getting anywhere, when in fact...
- 我們確實在前進  - 是的
- We are. - We are.
我現在當然哪兒也去不了
I'm certainly not getting anywhere at the moment.
加入俱樂部吧
Join the club.
我想這是你的命運
I think that's your lot.
請在這個小盒子裡 捐獻點什麼吧
Please leave a contribution in the little box.
你敢！那是我的
Don't you dare! Them's mine.
我想我可以捐出這個
Well, I guess I can spare this.
你沒有必要把那個給他
Oh, you didn't have to give him that.
他告訴你一些事情了
He didn't tell you nothin'.
好了 兩個蠢材上當了
Well, then. There go a couple of suckers.
啊 當你的帽子真刺激
Ah, it's so stimulating being your hat.
為什麼…為什麼你那麼說…
Why... Why did you say that...
說我是你的朋友？
about my being your friend?
因為你就是我的朋友
Because you are.
你可能不是我真正的朋友 但在這裡你是我唯一的朋友
You may not be much of a friend, but you're the only one I've got here.
你聽到什麼嗎？
Do you hear something?
- 沒有 一切正常  - 朋友
- No, it's all right. - Friend.
我喜歡這樣
I like that.
以前我從來沒有朋友
I ain't never been no one's friend before.
- 再見！  - 等一等
- Good-bye! - Wait a minute.
- 留著我的東西  - 你是不是我的朋友？
- Keep the stuff. - Are you my friend or not?
不 我不是 霍格沒有朋友
No, I'm not. Hoggle ain't no one's friend.
他照顧他自己 跟其他人一樣
He looks after himself, like everyone.
霍格的朋友就是他自己
Hoggle is Hoggle's friend.
霍格 你這個膽小鬼！
Hoggle, you coward!
我才不怕
Well, I'm not afraid.
在這裡經常眼見不為實
Things aren't always what they seem in this place.
試試這個吧 大雪人！
Try on this for size, you big yeti!
我們抓到你了 怪物！
We've got you now, fuzz ball!
一起來吧
All together now.
要是我有東西 扔過去就好了
If only I had something to throw.
咬他！咬他！
Sock it to him! Sock it to him!
怎麼回事？誰關燈？ 我看不見！
What happened? Who turned out the light? I can't see!
- 你幹嘛咬我？  - 誰咬誰？
- Why'd you bite me? - Who bite who?
誰咬我？誰咬我？
Who bite me? Who bite me?
- 我看不見！  - 發生什麼事？
- I can't see! - What is going on?
撤退！
Retreat!
誰咬我？
Who bit me?
噢 我心愛的生魚片！
Oh, my aching sushi!
停止
Now, stop that.
你就這樣對待救你的人的嗎？
Is that any way to treat someone who's trying to help you?
你要我放你下來嗎？
Don't you want me to help you down?
放下魯德
Ludo down.
魯德？
Ludo?
是你的名字嗎？
Is that your name?
你是一頭可愛的野獸
You seem like such a nice beast.
我真的希望你跟你的外表一樣友好
Well, I certainly hope you are what you seem to be.
堅持一下 我放你下來
Just hang on. I'll get you down.
就好了
Just a second.
對不起！
I'm sorry!
魯德 你受傷了嗎？
Ludo, are you hurt?
朋友？
Friend?
是的 魯德
That's right, Ludo.
我是莎拉
I'm Sarah.
莎拉
Sarah.
起來吧 我幫你
Here, let me help you.
你還好嗎？
Are you okay?
莎拉是朋友
Sarah friend.
等一等
Now, wait. Just a second.
- 我想問你一些東西 魯德  - 什麼？
- I want to ask you something, Ludo. - What?
我得去迷宮中心的城堡 你知道怎麼去嗎？
I have to get to the castle at the labyrinth's center. Do you know the way?
- 不知道  - 你也不知道啊？
- No. - You don't know either, huh?
有人知道如何走出迷宮就好了
I wonder if anyone knows how to get through this labyrinth.
走出迷宮 走出迷宮
Get through the labyrinth. Get through the labyrinth.
可以肯定… 她永遠也走不出迷宮
One thing for sure... she'll never get through the labyrinth.
喂
Hey.
它們從哪來？
Where did they come from?
你說呢？
What do you think?
兩個醜面孔我們挑哪個呢？
Which shall we choose out of these two ugly characters?
盯著人看是不禮貌的！
It's very rude to stare!
對不起我只是在想 該挑哪一扇門而已
I'm sorry. I was just wondering which door to choose.
- 什麼？  - 問他沒用
- What? - It's no good asking him.
- 他是徹底聾了  - 不要含著東西說話
- He's as deaf as a post. - Don't talk with your mouth full.
- 我沒有含著東西說話！  - 等一等
- I'm not talking with my mouth full! - Wait a second.
- 我聽不懂你的話  - 你說什麼了？
- I can't understand you. - What were you saying?
- 把那個東西拿掉真好啊  - 你剛才說什麼？
- It is so good to get that thing out. - What were you saying?
我說問他沒用 他是完全聾了
I said, it's no good talking to him. He's as deaf as a post.
咕噥咕噥 你真是一個健談的同事
Mumble, mumble. You're a wonderful conversational companion.
你會說！你在呻吟而已！
You can talk! All you do is moan!
沒用 我聽不見
No good. Can't hear you.
- 這些門通向哪裡？  - 什麼？
- Where do these doors lead? - What?
我可不知道 我們只是門環而已
Search me. We're just the knockers.
- 我怎麼過去？  - 啊？
- How do I get through? - Huh?
敲門門就會開
Knock, and the door will open.
我不想再含著這個東西
I don't want that thing back in my mouth.
- 好吧 我要敲門  - 嗯
- Come on. I want to knock. - Mm-mmm.
他不想再含著那個東西 是嗎？
Doesn't want his ring back in his mouth, eh?
我可沒有責備他
Can't say I blame him.
- 對不起  - 沒什麼 我習慣了
- Sorry. - That's all right. I'm used to it.
來吧
Come on.
歡迎
You're welcome.
他是一個活潑的小傢伙 我想我要叫他佳拉斯
He's a lively little chap. I think I'll call him Jareth.
我注意他好久了
He's got my eyes.
魯德害怕
Ludo scared.
喔 把手給我吧
Aw, give me your hand.
來吧
Come on.
你這麼大塊還怕啊
Imagine a big thing like you being scared.
是的
Yeah.
看啊 魯德？ 沒什麼好害怕的
See, Ludo? There's nothing to be afraid of.
魯德 你在哪裡？
Ludo, where are you?
霍格 救命啊！
Hoggle, help!
- 我來了 莎拉  - 幸虧有你啊
- I'm comin', Sarah. - Well, if it isn't you.
你去哪裡？
And where are you going?
那個小女孩讓我摔倒了…
Well, the little lady gave me the slip...
但是現在我聽到她在叫我…
but I just hears her now...
所以我打算把她帶回入口處…
so I was about to lead her back to the beginning...
按照你的要求
like you told me.
- 我明白了  - 魯德！
- I see. - Ludo!
我還以為你要回去幫她呢
For one moment I thought you were running to help her.
但在我警告你 以後就不認為了
But no, not after my warnings.
- 那是愚蠢的  - 你說對了！
- That would be stupid. - Oh, you bet it would!
在你警告之後我還幫她？
Me help her after your warnings?
- 噢 可憐的赫格特  - 霍格
- Oh, dear. Poor Hoghead. - Hoggle.
我剛剛發現 你可愛的珠寶不見了
I've just noticed your lovely jewels are missing.
噢 真的不見了
Oh, yes, so they are.
我可愛的珠寶 讓我想一想
My lovely jewels. Let me think.
我去找 但我先要把那個小女孩帶到…
I better find 'em, but first I'm off to take the little lady...
迷宮的入口處 就像我們計劃的那樣
back to the beginning of the labyrinth, just like we planned.
等等
Wait.
我有個更好的計劃
I've got a much better plan.
拿給她
Give her this.
這是…什麼？
Wha... What is it?
禮物
It's a present.
它不會傷害小女孩 是嗎？
It ain't gonna hurt the little lady, is it?
幹嘛這麼擔心？
Why the concern?
- 我不想傷害她  - 噢 霍格布林
- I won't do nothin' to harm her. - Oh, come, come, Hogbrain.
我很驚訝你被她迷惑了
I'm surprised at you losing your head over a girl.
我沒有
I ain't lost my head.
你沒有想到一個小女孩會…
You don't think a young girl could ever like...
喜歡你這樣的無賴 不是嗎？
a repulsive little scab like you, do you?
她說我們是…
She said we was...
知心朋友？
Bosom companions?
朋友？
Friends?
- 無所謂  - 你要把那個給她…
- Don't matter. - You'll give her that...
不然我就把你扔進永久惡臭的沼澤…
or I'll tip you straight into the Bog of Eternal Stench...
讓你眨眼都來不及
before you can blink.
遵命
Yes. Right.
還有霍格…
And Hoggle...
如果她親你 我就把你變成王子
if she ever kisses you, I'll turn you into a prince.
你…你會嗎？
You... You will?
惡臭沼澤的王子
Prince of the Land of Stench.
魯德？
Ludo?
發生什麼事？
What's going on?
- 你們想幹嘛？  - 什麼我們？
- What do you want? - What, us?
我們剛剛開心完
We're just after having a good time.
對！
That's right!
DAVID BOWIE - CHILLY DOWN
轉
Roll 'em.
蛇眼！
Snake eyes!
喂女孩！
Hey, lady!
前面！
Fore!
喂聽著
Hey, listen up.
來吧！
Come on!
喂喂！ 她的頭不會掉下來
Hey, hey! Her head don't come off.
當然不會！
Of course it doesn't!
- 她說得對 頭被粘住了  - 喂女孩
- She's right. It's stuck on. - Hey, lady.
有那樣的頭你還想去哪裡？
Where you going with a head like that?
喂 我知道我們可以做什麼 把她的頭拿掉！
Hey, man, I know what we can do. Take off her head!
對 把她撕開
Yeah, let's take her apart.
女孩 那是他的頭
Lady, that's his head.
- 那是我的頭！  - 那是我的朋友
- That's my head! - That's a friend of mine.
你在幹嘛？
What are you doing?
喂！等等！
Hey! Wait!
喂 女孩…
Hey, lady...
把別人的頭扔掉是違反規則的
it's against the rules to throw other people's heads.
你只能扔自己的頭
You're only allowed to throw your own head.
對
Yeah, that's right.
裁判在哪裡？
Where's the referee?
我們要把你的頭拿掉
We'll just take your head off.
- 攔住她  - 回來 小女孩
- Somebody stop her. - Come back, little lady.
- 來玩遊戲  - 對我 們要扔你的頭
- Play the game. - Yeah, we're going to throw your head.
你不能退出遊戲 還沒結束
You can't quit. The game's not over.
- 喂 女孩！  - 走開！
- Hey, lady! - Leave me alone!
- 我們要罰球  - 你想拿掉你的頭嗎？
- We get a free throw. - Don't you want to take your head off?
- 她當然想了  - 抓住繩子！
- Of course she does. - Grab it!
- 你想和我們一樣嗎？  - 走開
- Don't you want to look like us? - Leave me alone.
抓住她！抓住她！
We want her! Get us all!
如果你玩 我們會把你的胳膊拿掉！
If you play, we'll take off your arms!
- 或者拿掉你的耳朵  - 你不需要兩隻耳朵
- Or we'll take off your ear. - You don't need two ears.
- 遊戲快結束了  - 時間到
- Game's almost over. - Time's up.
- 走開  - 霍格 你來救我了
- Go away. - Hoggle, you've come to help me.
別親我！別親我！
Don't kiss me! Don't kiss me!
不 不 不要！
No, no, no!
霍格 小心
Hoggle, hold on.
噢 我的天
Oh, my God.
噢 這是什麼？
Oh, what is it?
永久惡臭的沼澤！
The Bog of Eternal Stench!
我從未聞過這種東西 好像…
I never smelled anything like it. It's like...
別管它像什麼 它是永久惡臭的沼澤
It doesn't matter what it's like. It's a Bog of Eternal Stench.
救我！
Help!
堅持住
Hold on.
你為什麼要這麼做？
What did you have to go and do a thing like that for?
做什麼？
Do what?
- 你是說我救你嗎？  - 什麼？不是
- You mean rescue you? - What? No.
你親我了
You kissed me.
噢 糟糕
Oh, my gosh.
別裝模做樣了
Don't pretend to be so hard.
我知道你是回來救我 我知道你是我朋友
I know you came back to help me, and I know that you're my friend.
我沒有也不是
Did not. Am not.
我只是回來拿我的財產
I just come to get me property back.
還有…
Oh, and...
給你…給你…
give you... give you...
給我什麼？
Give me what?
魯德！
Ludo!
很臭！
Smell!
霍格到哪去了？
Where's Hoggle?
別壓著我！
Get off of me!
在這裡
Here.
沒事 這是魯德 它也是我的朋友
Oh, no, it's okay. This is Ludo. He's a friend too.
什麼？
A what?
臭！
Smell!
你說得對
You're right.
天哪
Oh, my God.
有座橋
There's a bridge.
來吧
Come on.
小心
Watch it.
踩到這些東西 你就永遠都會臭
You step in this stuff and you'll stink forever.
停！
Stop!
- 我說停  - 麻煩你讓我們過去吧
- Stop, I say. - Please, we have to get across.
沒有我的允許 誰都別想過去
Without my permission, no one may cross.
我們沒多少時間了！
Please, I only have a little time left!
我們必須走過這個沼澤
We've gotta get out of this stench.
很臭
Smell bad.
- 臭？你說什麼臭？  - 這裡很臭
- Stench? Of what speaketh thou? - This smell.
- 我什麼都聞不到  - 你開玩笑吧
- I smell nothing. - Oh, you're joking.
我靠嗅覺生存的
But I live by my sense of smell.
空氣又香又甜 沒有我的允許誰都不能過去！
The air is sweet and fragrant, and none may pass without my permission!
很臭
Smell bad.
走開！
Oh, get out of my way!
我警告你 我發誓要盡忠職守！
I warn thee, I'm sworn to do my duty!
- 求求你讓我們過去吧  - 別動！
- Come on. Let us get across. - Hold!
聽著我不想傷害你們
Listen, I don't want to have to hurt you.
你要幹嘛？
What are you doing?
放開我的武器！
Let go of my staff, sir!
那好 讓我來征服這座山
All right then. I can conquer this mountain.
你必須幹得更好才行
Thou must do better than that.
投降了？啊？
Give up? Huh?
夠了！
Enough!
以前 我打架未縫敵手
Before this day, never have I met my match in battle.
這個高貴的武士 讓我透不過氣
Yet this noble knight has fought me to a standstill.
- 你沒事吧 魯德？  - 臭！
- Are you all right, Ludo? - Smell!
原來你叫魯德 我是迪迪莫斯 我服輸了
Sir Ludo, if that's thy name, now I, Sir Didymus, yield to thee.
來 讓我們從此做兄弟吧…
Come, let us be brothers henceforth...
為正義共同作戰！
and fight for the right as one!
- 非常謝謝你  - 魯德有兄弟了
- Thank you very much. - Ludo get brother.
一言為定
Steady.
- 很高興認識你 魯德  - 太好了 來吧
- Well met, Sir Ludo. - Good. Come on.
等等！你忘了我的誓言 小姐
Wait a minute! You forget my sacred vow, my lady.
- 我不能讓你過去  - 但是你說魯德是你的兄弟
- I cannot let you pass. - But you said Ludo is your brother.
我曾立誓 要誓死捍衛它
I have taken an oath, and I must defend it to the death.
- 很臭！  - 那好
- The smell! - Okay.
我們冷靜下來想想 你到底發了什麼誓？
Let's handle this thing logically. What exactly have you sworn?
我以血發誓 如果沒有我的允許…
I have sworn with my lifeblood no one shall pass this way...
任何人都不准過橋
without my permission.
那麼我們可以得到你的允許嗎？
Well, may we have your permission?
這個我…
Well, l...
- 好吧  - 謝謝你 你太好了
- Yes. - Thank you, noble sir.
不用謝
My lady.
- 噢  - 不要怕 小姐
- Uh-oh. - Have no fear, sweet lady.
這座橋有一千年歷史了
This bridge has lasted for a thousand years.
- 看來還很堅固  - 霍格！
- It seemed solid enough. - Hoggle!
不用怕 可愛的小姐 我來救你
Fear not, fair maiden. I will save thee.
怎麼回事
Somehow.
魯德 你不去救人 反而在這裡大聲吼叫？
Sir Ludo, canst thou sit by and howl when yon maiden needs our help?
- 太不可思議了 魯德  - 兄弟！
- That's incredible, Ludo. - My brother!
你能聚集石頭？
Canst thou summon up the very rocks?
當然石頭是朋友
Sure. Rocks friends.
- 上來吧  - 謝謝你 霍格
- Here. - Thanks, Hoggle.
小心 魯德
Be careful, Ludo.
等等我
Wait for me.
安伯希斯 沒事了 出來吧
Ambrosious, it's all right. You can come out now.
來吧 好傢伙
Come on. That-a boy.
我忠心的戰馬來吧
My loyal steed. Steady.
前進
Forward. Steady, boy.
來吧 安伯希斯 閉上眼睛直走
Come on, Ambrosious. Just close your eyes and go.
我們走吧
Let's get out of here.
讓一讓 謝謝
Excuse us. Thank you.
如果我是你 我不會那樣做
I wouldn't do that, if I were you.
不要逼我 我不能拿給她
Oh, please, I can't give it to her.
走吧 我們在天黑前應該能到達城堡
Come on then. We should reach the castle well before day.
看 莎拉 這就是你要找的東西嗎？
Look, Sarah, is this what you're trying to find?
這個小傢伙多麻煩啊 但是很快就不會了
So much trouble over such a little thing, but not for long.
她很快會忘記你 我的寶貝
She'll soon forget all about you, my fine fellow.
只要霍格把我的禮物給她…
Just as soon as Hoggle gives her my present...
她就會忘掉所有的東西
then she'll forget everything.
是我的肚子還是你的 安伯希斯？
Is that my stomach or yours, Ambrosious?
餓了
Hungry.
是啊 但我們不能停下
Yeah. Well, we can't stop now.
或許我們能找到野果吃
Maybe we can find some berries or something.
幹嘛？
Yeah?
給你
Here.
謝謝！
Thank you!
你真是救命恩人
You're a lifesaver.
味道很奇怪
This tastes strange.
你放了什麼？
What have you done?
噢 該死的佳拉斯
Oh, damn you, Jareth.
我真該死
And damn me too.
一切都在跳動
Everything's dancing.
太好了 停哇 安伯希斯 哇！
Yea, verily. Whoa, Ambrosious, whoa!
城堡就在那邊 小姐
The castle doth lie yonder, my lady.
小姐？
My lady?
小姐？小姐？
My lady? My lady?
[DAVID BOWIE - AS THE WORLD FALLS DOWN
噢她不會原諒我
Oh, she'll never forgive me.
我做了什麼？
What have I done?
我失去了唯一的朋友
I've lost my only friend.
我失去了朋友
That's what I've done.
我剛才在幹什麼？
What was I doing?
下來！
Get off my back!
幹嘛不想想你要去哪裡…
Why don't you look where you're going...
小女孩 啊？
young woman, hmm?
- 我在找呢  - 哈？哈？
- I was looking. - Huh? Huh?
你打算去哪裡啊？
Where were you going, hmm?
我忘記了
I don't remember.
你不知道要去哪裡 找也沒用
You can't look where you're going if you don't know where you're going.
我在找東西
I was searching for something.
看看
Look here.
蘭斯洛特？
Lancelot?
謝謝
Thank you.
這就是你要找的 是嗎親愛的？
That's what you were looking for, wasn't it, my dear?
是的 我剛才忘了
Yes. I forgot.
那麼你為什麼…
Now, why don't you...
不進來…
come in here...
看看還有沒有其它東西…
and see if there's anything else...
你喜歡的啊？
you'd like, hmm?
只是一個夢
It was just a dream.
我做了個夢 蘭斯洛特
I dreamed it all, Lancelot.
但是很真實
But it was so real.
去看看爸爸回來沒有 好嗎？
Let's go see if Daddy's back, okay?
最好留在這裡 親愛的
Better to stay in here, dear. Yes.
外面沒有你要的東西 沒有！
There's nothing you want out there. No!
看看這裡有什麼？
Oh, what have we got here?
蘭斯洛特
Lancelot.
你可愛的小兔子 你喜歡可愛的小兔子
Your little bunny rabbit. You like your little bunny rabbit.
不是嗎？ 是的 是的 給你
Don't you? Yes, yes. There you go.
還有小人偶 你記得小人偶 是嗎？
There's Betsy Bou. You remember Betsy Bou, don't you?
對對
Yes, yes.
那麼我們還有什麼？ 這是什麼？我們看看
Now, then, what else have we got? What's this? Let's have a look.
是個鉛筆盒 裡面還有很多鉛筆
It's a pencil box. Got lots of pencils in it too.
這是你的熊貓拖鞋 你很喜歡它們的
Here's your panda slippers. You know how much you like them.
你不想它們被扔掉吧 給你 很好
You never wanted them thrown away. There they are. That's right.
現在還有什麼？ 噢 一隻小馬
Okay, now then, what else? Oh, it's little Horsey.
你喜歡小馬 不是嗎 親愛的？
You love little Horsey, don't you, dear?
看看這個！ 你有畫畫遊戲 給你
And look at this! You got a printing game, you have.
這是寶物 你喜歡 對不對 親愛的？
Oh, here's a treasure. You'll want that, won't you, my dear?
好的 試一下 化化妝
Yes, go on, put it on. Make yourself up.
這是可愛的弗羅茜 你喜歡 給你
Here's dear old Flopsy. You'll want her. There you go.
對了 對了
Oh, yes. Ah, oh, yes.
查理熊 好的 給你小熊
Charlie Bear. Right. There's Charlie Bear for you.
我在找一些東西
There was something I was looking for.
啊 別亂說
Ah, don't talk nonsense.
都在這裡了 你要的都在這裡了
It's all here. Everything you've ever cared about is all right here.
這是你的糖果店玩具
There's your little toy candy shop.
「經歷數之不盡的艱難…
"Through dangers untold...
和無盡的險阻…
and hardships unnumbered...
我終於到了去城堡的路…
I fought my way here to the castle...
要穿越格布林鬼城…
beyond the Goblin City...
找回被你偷走的小孩」
to take back the child that you have stolen. "
怎麼了 親愛的？ 不喜歡你的玩具嗎？
What's the matter, my dear? Don't you like your toys?
這些都是廢物
It's all junk.
那麼這個呢？
Well, what about this?
這個不是廢物吧？
This is not junk, eh?
這是！
Yes, it is!
我要去救托比！
I have to save Toby!
小姐！
My lady!
你沒事吧？
Are you all right?
美麗的小姐 你沒事真是太好了
Fair maiden. Thank goodness thou art safe at last.
- 我們到哪裡了？  - 莎拉回來了
- Where are we? - Sarah back.
小姐 我們就快到了
My lady, we're almost there.
那是格布林鬼城的門
Those are the gates to the Goblin City.
魯德 迪迪莫斯
Ludo, Sir Didymus.
趕快走吧 時間不多了
Let's go quickly. We don't have much time.
- 好  - 好吧 安伯希斯
- Yeah. - Right, Ambrosious.
前進
Forward.
去吧
You know.
開門 打開門
Open up. Open the door.
迪迪莫斯 我們得悄悄進去
Sir Didymus, we must go quietly.
開門 趕快開門！
Open up. Open up right now!
你會吵醒守衛
You'll wake the guard.
安靜
Quiet.
來吧 把他們全吵醒！
Well, let them all wake up!
我要把你們全殺死！
I shall fight you all to the death!
拜託 迪迪莫斯 我求你安靜下來
Please, Sir Didymus, for my sake, hush.
當然可以 為了你 什麼都可以
But of course. For thee, anything.
- 但我不是懦夫？  - 對
- But I'm not a coward? - No.
- 我的嗅覺很靈敏？  - 是的
- And my sense of smell is keen? - Oh, yes.
那麼我就可以隨時隨地戰鬥！
Then I shall fight anyone anywhere, anyplace, any time!
我們知道！
We know!
安靜下來
Now hush.
安靜
Quietly.
安伯希斯 安靜
Ambrosious, be quiet now.
我不明白為什麼要安靜
I don't see why we have to be so quiet.
只是一個格布林鬼城而已
It's only a Goblin City.
我感覺有麻煩了
I smell trouble.
小心 魯德
Come on, Ludo.
不
Oh, no.
那是什麼？
What is that?
誰想過去？
Who goes?
小心！
Watch out!
安伯希斯 過來好嗎？
Ambrosious, will you come here?
馬上過來！
Come here right now!
請你過來好嗎？你讓我很難堪
Will you please come into the open? You're embarrassing me.
小心！
Look out!
走吧
Get out of there.
你想幹嘛？
What are you doing?
走開！
Bombs away!
不是很好
That wasn't very nice.
輪到我了
My turn now.
怎麼駕駛？
How do you drive this thing?
扔掉斧頭！
Drop the ax!
我在想辦法
I'm trying.
下來吧
Come here at once.
發生什麼事？
What's happened?
哪一個是後退？
Where's reverse?
離開那兒 霍格！
Get out of there, Hoggle!
棄船
Abandon ship.
霍格 你沒事吧？
Hoggle, are you all right?
我不奢望你的原諒 我不為自己的所作所為感到內疚
I'm not asking to be forgiven. I ain't ashamed of nothin' I did.
佳拉斯叫我把桃子給你
Jareth made me give you that peach.
我不介意你怎麼看我 我說過我是懦夫
I don't care what you think of me. I told you I was a coward.
我想和你做朋友
I ain't interested in being friends.
我原諒你
I forgive you.
你…真的嗎？
You... You do?
我要稱讚你 你的勇氣可嘉
And I commend you. Rarely have I seen such courage.
你是一個勇敢的人 霍格
You are a valiant man, Sir Hoggle.
- 是嗎？  - 是的
- I am? - Yeah.
霍格和魯德是朋友
Hoggle and Ludo friends.
- 真的嗎？  - 真的
- We are? - Yeah.
這是你的東西
Here are your things.
謝謝你幫忙
Thanks for your help.
那麼我們還等什麼？
Well, what are we waiting for?
一起把那個叫佳拉斯的老鼠抓出來
Let's get the rat who calls himself Jareth.
好走吧
Right. Come on.
安伯希斯 現在安全了 不要怕
Ambrosious, it's safe now. Nothing to be afraid of.
陛下！
Your Highness!
- 陛下 那個女孩…  - 什麼？
- Your Highness, the girl... - What?
吃了桃子 忘記了所有事的  - 她怎麼了？
- Who ate the peach, forgot everything. - What of her?
她和一隻妖怪來了 還有你手下的迪迪莫斯和侏儒
She's here with the monster and Sir Didymus and the dwarf who works for you.
- 什麼？  - 他們朝城堡這邊來了！
- What? - They're on their way to the castle!
阻止她！叫守衛來 把嬰兒藏起來
Stop her! Call out the guards. Take the baby and hide it.
守衛！
Guards!
必須阻止她 趕快！
She must be stopped. Do something!
快行動 行動！
Come on, move. Move!
- 我想我們就快到了  - 哈 小菜一碟
- I think we're gonna make it. - Oh, piece of cake.
大伙停
Company, halt.
長矛準備！
Lances ready!
大炮發射！
Cannon, fire!
安伯希斯 掉頭 掉頭
Ambrosious, turn around. Turn about.
- 快 這邊  - 好吧 衝！
- Quick, this way. - All right. Charge!
不 不是那邊！
No, not that way!
你走錯了！
You're going the wrong way!
敵人在我們後面！
The battle's behind us!
安伯希斯 我們談談好嗎？
Ambrosious, can we please talk about this?
停！
Sit!
小心點 好嗎
Be careful. Okay.
這邊
Through here.
安伯希斯 站住
Ambrosious, stand still.
好吧來吧
Okay, come on, guys.
安伯希斯 如果你再不掉頭…
Ambrosious, if you don't turn around this second...
我就不餵你了
I will never feed you again.
這還差不多
That's better.
別擔心 安伯希斯 我想我們被包圍了
Don't worry, Ambrosious. I think we've got them surrounded.
迪迪莫斯！ 迪迪莫斯在哪裡？
Didymus! Where's Didymus?
開火！
Fire!
我打中了嗎？有沒有？
I hit something, yes? No?
我們要找到迪迪莫斯
We've got to find Didymus.
這邊
Down this way.
衝啊！
Charge!
呔呵！
Tallyho!
安伯希斯 你這個懦夫
Ambrosious, you coward.
快進去
Quick, in here.
魯德怎麼進來？
How's Ludo gonna get in?
你們被包圍了！
You in there, you're surrounded!
包圍？
Surrounded?
出去！魯德 守住屋頂！
Get out! Ludo, hold the roof!
- 接招！  - 餓了嗎？
- Take that! - Hungry?
安伯希斯 開門
Ambrosious, unlock this door.
玩夠了嗎？
So, had enough, have you?
放下你們的武器 我會讓你們好受點
Then throw down your weapons, and I'll see that you're well-treated.
下次再投降吧
Next time, surrender.
做的好！
Good grief!
停下
Steady, men.
停 不要動
Steady, men. Hold your ground.
當我沒說 逃命吧！
Okay, I take it back. Run for your lives!
我受夠了！我要睡覺
I've had enough! I'm going to bed.
出去！
Get out of my house!
哇 內爾！閃開！
Whoa, Nellie! Duck!
偏了！
Missed!
好來吧
Okay, come on.
開火！
Fire!
喂 我開火了
Hey, I just fired you.
唉唷 哎唷 哎唷！
Ouch, ouch, ouch!
這邊
This way.
我們抓到你們了！
Now we have you!
現在抓不到了
And now you don't.
沒問題
Hey, no problem.
- 迪迪莫斯！  - 來了！
- Sir Didymus! - Coming!
嘿喲 銀牌！
Hi-ho, Silver!
- 哇 好傢伙 哇太棒了  - 這邊
- Whoa, boy. Whoa, big fella. - This way.
停
Steady, boy.
好 上去 上
Ah, yes. Up we go. Up, up.
來吧 好樣的
Come on. Good boy.
來
Come on.
不
No.
好 走吧
Good boy. Come on.
- 他只有這條路走了  - 那麼 走吧
- That's the only way he could have gone. - Well, then, come on.
- 我必須自己去找他  - 為什麼？
- I have to face him alone. - But why?
因為開始時就是這樣
Because that's the way it's done.
好吧 如果開始是這樣…
Well, if that is the way it is done...
你就必須這樣去做
then that is the way you must do it.
但是如果你需要幫忙…
But should you need us...
是的 如果需要幫忙…
Yes, should you need us...
我會叫你們
I'll call.
謝謝 謝謝你們
Thank you, all of you.
托比！
Toby!
把孩子給我
Give me the child.
莎拉 小心了
Sarah, beware.
直到現在我都很仁慈 我也可以殘忍
I have been generous up until now, and I can be cruel.
仁慈？
Generous?
- 你做了什麼叫仁慈？  - 一切！
- What have you done that's generous? - Everything!
你要的一切我都做了
Everything that you have wanted, I have done.
你要我把小孩帶走 我做了
You asked that the child be taken. I took him.
你在我面前退縮 我很可怕
You cowered before me. I was frightening.
我重新定了時間
I have reordered time.
我把世界倒轉…
I have turned the world upside-down...
這一切都是為了你
and I have done it all for you.
為了滿足你 我身心疲倦
I am exhausted from living up to your expectations of me.
這還不算仁慈嗎？
Isn't that generous?
經歷數之不盡的艱難險阻…
Through dangers untold and hardships unnumbered...
我終於到了城堡 在格布林鬼城那裡
I have fought my way here to the castle beyond the Goblin City.
因為我的毅力同你一樣堅韌…
For my will is as strong as yours...
- 我的…  - 停止 等一等
- and my... - Stop. Wait.
看 莎拉
Look, Sarah.
看我給你什麼
Look what I'm offering you.
你的夢想
Your dreams.
我的國度一樣的偉大…
And my kingdom as great...
我只有小小的要求
I ask for so little.
讓我控制你…
Just let me rule you...
你就能得到你想要的一切
and you can have everything that you want.
國度一樣的偉大？
Kingdom as great?
該死的
Damn.
我怎麼也記不住這一行
I can never remember that line.
只要你敬畏我 愛我 聽我的話…
Just fear me, love me, do as I say...
我可以成為你的奴隸
and I will be your slave.
我的國度一樣的偉大… 我的國度一樣的偉大…
My kingdom as great... My kingdom as great...
你的法力並不強過我
You have no power over me.
托比
Toby.
給你
Here you are.
我現在把蘭斯洛特送給你
I'd like Lancelot to belong to you now.
我們回來了
We're home.
莎拉 你在家嗎？
Sarah, are you home?
在 我在家
Yeah. Yes, I'm home.
再見莎拉
Good-bye, Sarah.
記住 美麗的小姐…
Remember, fair maiden...
如果你需要我們…
should you need us...
對 如果你需要我們…
Yes, should you need us...
無論什麼原因…
for any reason at all...
我需要你 霍格
I need you, Hoggle.
真的？
You do?
不知道為什麼 但是…
I don't know why, but...
無論現在還是將來…
every now and again in my life...
不為任何原因 我需要你
for no reason at all, I need you.
需要你們大家
All of you.
真的？
You do?
為什麼不早說呢？
Well, why didn't you say so?
- 噢 魯德！  - 莎拉
- Oh, Ludo! - Sarah.
安伯希斯 好傢伙
Ambrosious, good boy, good boy.
我說 有人想玩拼字遊戲嗎？
I say, does anyone here want to play a game of Scrabble?
一你讓我想起了那個小孩
一什麼小孩？
- You remind me of the babe.
- What babe?
一有力量的小孩
一什麼力量？
- The babe with the power.
- What power?
巫術你
The power of voodoo. You do.
一我幹嘛？
一讓我想起了那個小孩
- Do what?
- Remind me of the babe.
一爸爸爸爸帶我離開這裡
一我今天聽說了一個地方
- Daddy, Daddy, get me out of here
- Heard about a place today
我在地下
l, I'm underground
不會再有傷害
Nothing ever hurts again
一聽說了一個地方
一爸爸帶我離開這裡
- Heard about a place today
- Daddy, get me out of here
到一個不會
再有傷害的地方
Where nothing ever hurts again
我想到地下
Wanna go underground
一爸爸爸爸帶我離開這裡
一我想到地下
- Daddy, Daddy, get me out of here
- Wanna go underground
一我在地下
一帶我到地下
- l, I'm underground
- Get me underground
一姐姐姐姐請帶我下去
一爸爸帶我離開
- Sister, sister, please take me down
- Daddy, get me out of here
我在地下
l, I'm underground
想到地下
Wanna go underground
爸爸爸爸
帶我離開這裡
Daddy, Daddy, get me out of here
沒有人會責怪你
No one can blame you
若你走開
For walking away
但太多的拒絕
But too much rejection
就不會有愛
No love injection
生活可能很容易
Life can be easy
但並不總是精彩
It's not always swell
別告訴我事實
會傷害人小女孩
Don't tell me truth hurts
little girl
因為那真的很傷害人
'Cause it hurts like hell
但是在地底下
But down in the underground
你會發現有人是真的
You'll find someone true
在地底
Down in the underground
一個寧靜地方
A land serene
一輪皎潔的月亮
A crystal moon
最好能是永遠
It's only forever
但它不會長久
Not long at all
迷失和孤獨的人
The lost and the lonely
這是地下
That's underground
地下
Underground
一爸爸爸爸帶我離開這裡
一今天聽說了一個地方
- Daddy, Daddy, get me out of here
- Heard about a place today
我在地下
l, I'm underground
不會再有傷害
Nothing ever hurts again
一今天聽說了一個地方
一爸爸帶我離開這裡
- Heard about a place today
- Daddy, get me out of here
到一個不會
再有傷害的地方
Where nothing ever hurts again
想到地下
Wanna go underground
一爸爸爸爸帶我離開這裡
一想到地下
- Daddy, Daddy, get me out of here
- Wanna go underground
一我在地下
一帶我到地下
- l, I'm underground
- Get me underground
一姐姐姐姐請帶我下去
一爸爸帶我離開這裡
- Sister, sister, please take me down
- Daddy, get me out of here
我在地下
l, I'm underground
想到地下
Wanna go underground
爸爸爸爸
帶我離開這裡
Daddy, Daddy, get me out of here
最好
It's only
最好能是永遠
It's only forever
但它不會長久
It's not long at all
迷失和孤獨的人
The lost and the lonely
這是地下
That's underground
地下
Underground
爸爸爸爸
帶我離開這裡
Daddy, Daddy, get me out of here
今天聽說了一個地方
Heard about a place today
一不會再有傷害
- Nothing ever hurts again
爸爸爸爸
帶我離開這裡
Daddy, Daddy, get me out of here
爸爸帶我離開這裡
Daddy, get me out of here
我在地下
l, I'm underground
想到地下
Wanna go underground
一姐姐姐姐請帶我下去
一想到地下
- Sister, sister, please take me down
- Wanna go underground
我在地下
l, I'm underground
一帶我到地下
一爸爸爸爸帶我離開這裡
- Get me underground
- Daddy, Daddy, get me out
想生活在地下
Wanna live underground